Paul Caffrey, 125 Maples Road, Wedgewood, Sandyford, Dublin 16 Mobile: 085 7101573 Email: paul.caffrey@gmail.com

Summary

For past year I have been Senior Software Developer at Citco Fund Services developing bespoke software within the Aexeo Information Technology team. Prior to this I was Senior Software Developer at Accenture for 8 years. I have extensive experience in application development.

Extensive technical skills, with ten years experience of Java. (Sun Certified Java Developer) I have more than 20 years experience working the IT sector.

Highly qualified: I have a primary degree in Electrial Engineering and an MSc in Computer Applications. My main interests are software development using Eclipse/Java/Spring/Hibernate and relational databases. I have an interest in the financial industry with a Dip FM in Financial Management.

Work Experience

Job Title: Senior Software Developer

Employer: Citco Fund Services

Dates: December 2012 to October 2012 Project: Cash Management Application

The role at Citco was to develop bespoke software for Cash Managemement.

My task was to develop new features such as Reporting and Reconciliation.

Reporting allowed reports to be deployed dynamically. Reporting on clients/funds/counterparties. Oracle Stored procedures are invoked by Spring and results displayed in C# Gridview. New reports can be dynamically deployed.

Reconciliation feature calculated fund balances and net liquidity values and compared against different systems.

The system is used daily by Citco Fund Services to verify cash balances for clients such as Goldman Sachs.

The CashManagement system is a transactional system based on Spring MVC, Spring JdbcTemplate, Hibernate, Websphere and .NET VisualStudio front end. Development using MyEclipse. Oracle and Sybase databases. The infrastructure included maven, JIRA, Bamboo, Artifactory.

Full software delivery life cycle from gathering requirements to design and development.

Job Title: Senior Software Developer

Employer: Accenture Ireland

Dates: October 2004 to December 2012

Project: Data warehousing and Business Intelligence

During my time at Revenue Commissioners I developed numerous applications.

Apache Tomcat Portal

Within Accenture I was mainly based at the Revenue Commissioners Dublin city centre.

I has overall responsibility for the Business Intelligence capability at Revenue Commissioners.

For several years I developed web applications for Business Intelligence applications. The portal is used every day by more than 3000 users.

I was the main person responsible for this system which is used successfully daily with thousands of queries and reports.

Team Leadership

Team lead and Performance Reviews.

Updating plans and providing metrics reports

Paul Caffrey, 125 Maples Road, Wedgewood, Sandyford, Dublin 16 Mobile: 085 7101573 Email: paul.caffrey@gmail.com

Full year and mid-year reviews and ratings Providing technical guidance and advice Creating Plans and Estimates

Property, Dividends, VAT Information Exchange, Rental Accommodation Scheme, Foreign Property Applications

I developed a number of application using Eclipse/ Java / Spring / Hibernate / JDBC / JSP / HTML / JavaScript These are original web applications for use by the Revenue Commissioners users.

Applications connected to Ingres database. Source control was CVS.

Integration with Dun and Bradstreet, OneSource, Bureau Van Dyke

Interface to third party websites such as Dun and Bradstreet, OneSource, Bureau Van Dyke websites Development of webservices using WSDL and soapUI

Bank Financial Suspicious Transactions Fidol II

I was on the team to develop the receipt and acknowledgement of "suspicious transactions" from Bank institutions.

This was a PKI Email solution to decrypt emails from Financial Institutions (PKCS and PGP)

This was a business critical part of the Revenue Commissioners suite of software and was used successfully daily to receive Suspicious Transactions (STRs).

Dimensional modelling

Jaspersoft/JasperAnalysis/JasperReports/Mondrian OLAP Cubes Talend Studio Extract, Transform and Load Extensive use of SQL and Ingres database Search Performance: SQL Query Execution Plan

Columnar Database

Extensive use of Actian Vectorwise columnar database as backend to Business Intelligence applications and also applied to OLAP Cubes.

Managing the Infrastructure

Setting up of Test environments, Upgrade of environment, Tomcat and Java versions.

Developing support applications such as User Administration security application, Web log usage, Monitoring of tomcat searches, Tomcat access log analysis, Troubleshooting any technical issues.

Name Address Matching

Development of large scale matching using and name/address/phone/email to match Revenue customers to 3rd party data sources.

Numerous sources were matched to build up a profile of customers and display this information on the Businesss Intelligence portal.

This was also used for the "Local Property Tax" and was instrumental in identifying owners of the 2 million residential properties in the country.

Geodirectory GIS application

Integration of GIS into Revenue Commissioners

Development of GIS solution to display customer location on Google Maps integrated into the customer profile.

Address-only matching to obtain latitude/longitude.

GeoCoding customer addresses using Geodirectory, Google maps and Yahoo PlaceFinder GIS application development using GeoXml3 and Google Fusion Tables for reporting purposes.

Paul Caffrey, 125 Maples Road, Wedgewood, Sandyford, Dublin 16 Mobile: 085 7101573 Email: paul.caffrey@gmail.com

Technology

Applications developed using Eclipse and SpringSource ToolSuite

OpenSource tools including: Ingres, Ant, Junit, Maven, Hudson, JasperSoft, Talend, Mondrian, Spring MVC and Webflow.

Recently completed Spring 3.0 training.

Job Title: Senior Software Engineer

Employer: Interactive Enterprise Dates: Sept 1999 to Sept 2004

Nature of company: Developing broadband provisioning solutions

Role: Leading the Technical Architecture team

Development of Session Control, Transactions and scalability in custom-developed CORBA engine

Developed in C++ and Java Oracle Database, Servlet, JSP Python interpreter extensions.

 $Interactive\ Enterprise\ was\ a\ Irish\ startup\ company\ special ising\ in\ the\ business\ of\ provisioning\ digital\ set-top$

boxes and services.

Job Title: Senior Software Engineer

Employer: Informix

Dates: Aug 1993 to Aug. 1999

Project: Developing Informix RDBMS Product Suite

Role: Senior Software Engineer

Platform engineering to re-platform Informix suite of products to Unix platforms such as Linux, HP-UX and

Hitachi-UX

In depth knowledge of Unix Systems programming, pipes, sockets, tcp-ip, shared memory, IPC,

Database Server, Client, 4GL, Data Warehouse

C programming. Multi-threading.

Use of ClearCase source code control software.

Job Title: Software Test Engineer

Employer: Amdahl Jan. 1988 to Aug. 1993

Project: Test Automation

Role: Test Engineer and Software Developer

Development of Test Automation Software using product called Automator.

Installation of Sun Solaris workstations and development of GUI applications using X/Windows and OSF/Motif

Use of Amdahl Unix on mainframe.

Language Skills

Good French and German

Educational Background

Sun Certified Java Programmer: 2007

Sun Microsystems Prometric Exam

Paul Caffrey, 125 Maples Road, Wedgewood, Sandyford, Dublin 16 Mobile: 085 7101573 Email: paul.caffrey@gmail.com

ACCA Qualification in Financial Management: 2004 (part-time)

Dublin Business School

Postgraduate Education 1990 to 1992 (part-time)

MSc Computer Applications Dublin City University

Third Level Education 1983 to 1987

University College Cork BE Electrical Engineering 2nd Class Honours Grade I

Secondary Education 1978 to 1983

Christian Brothers School Midleton Co. Cork